Guide to the Vassar College Folklore Foundation Records, 1919-1938
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Vassar College Folklore Foundation Records
1919-1938
Vassar College. Folklore Foundation
0.6 cubic feet (3 boxes)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Correspondence of Martha Warren Beckwith concerning research inquiries, folklore topics, conferences, papers, lectures, distribution of the Foundation publications, and other activities of the Foundation, 1919-1938.
Administrative History
The Folklore Foundation was founded in 1920 as the gift of an anonymous donor. Martha Beckwith was hired to run the program, which was meant primarily as a research and not a teaching program. The foundation ended in 1938 when Beckwith retired.
Scope and Content Note
Correspondence of Martha Warren Beckwith concerning research inquiries, folklore topics, conferences, papers, lectures, distribution of the Foundation publications, and other activities of the Foundation, 1919-1938.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the
regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
without any additional restrictions.
Related Materials
Henry Noble MacCracken Papers
A cylinder recorder from the Folklore Foundation is housed in the Vassar College Music Library.
Subject Headings
Names:
Beckwith, Martha Warren, 1871-1959
Subjects:
Folklore--Research; Folklore--Study and teaching
VCL Categories
Vassar College Special Programs and Projects
Encoding Information
Encoded by Elizabeth Clarke, April 2007.
Acquisition Information
Transfer.
Container List
- Annual reports, 1920-1926 (Folder 1.1)
- Annual reports, 1927/1928, 1928/1929 (Folder 1.2)
- Annual reports, 1930/1931, 1931/1932 (Folder 1.3)
- Annual reports, 1934/1935 (Folder 1.4)
- [Final] annual report with addenda summarizing the history and activities of the Folklore Foundation, 1937/1938 (Folder 1.5)
- Correspondence — Distribution of Publications (Folders 1.6-1.8)
- Correspondence — Activities of the Department (Folder 1.9)
- General Correspondence — A - Benedict (Folder 2.10)
- General Correspondence — Bentley - Burchenal (Folder 2.11)
- General Correspondence — C (Folder 2.12)
- General Correspondence — Davis - Herzog (Folder 2.13)
- General Correspondence — Howe (Folder 2.14)
- General Correspondence — J (Folder 3.15)
- General Correspondence — K-M (Folder 3.16)
- General Correspondence — N-S (Folder 3.17)
- General Correspondence — T-Z (Folder 3.18)